<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sentiment Analysis on Bryan Schafroth Portfolio</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4321/tags/sentiment-analysis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sentiment Analysis on Bryan Schafroth Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4321/tags/sentiment-analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sentiment Analysis and Social Media Use Policy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2019/02/18/sentiment-analysis-and-social-media-use-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2019/02/18/sentiment-analysis-and-social-media-use-policy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;    The data scientist should read all agreements and policies of the specific social media site before engaging in data mining for sentiment analysis. The agreements and policies are carefully written by social media companies to protect users, the social company, and the developers. On Twitter&amp;rsquo;s Developers Agreement under &amp;ldquo;VII. Other Important Terms&amp;rdquo; there is a guide on what information is available and how it should not be used (Twitter Developer, May 25, 2018). By acknowledging the agreement developers who have access to Twitter data cannot use the data to give public agencies the information for surveillance, investigating, or tracking users and their content (Twitter Developer, May 25, 2018, VII, section 1). A data scientist should be made aware of the use of the data analyzed. The agreement stresses that any collected data not be used for investigation, surveillance, analysis, or research that discriminates against individuals or groups and must adhere to the users&amp;rsquo; &amp;ldquo;reasonable expectation of privacy.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
