<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Public Data on Bryan Schafroth Portfolio</title>
    <link>/categories/public-data/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Public Data on Bryan Schafroth Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/public-data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Justice Aided with Data Science</title>
      <link>/post/2019/02/25/social-justice-aided-with-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/02/25/social-justice-aided-with-data-science/</guid>
      <description>The social justice issue that data science can aid with is life expectancy throughout the world. The social justice issue is a project that was brought to the world&amp;rsquo;s attention by Hans Rosling, and you can see his presentation on Youtube in the references. He compared the life expectancy to the Gross Domestic Product per capita (GPD) of the countries, and plotting the data found a strong correlation between GDP and the life span of the Country&amp;rsquo;s citizens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sentiment Analysis and Social Media Use Policy</title>
      <link>/post/2019/02/18/sentiment-analysis-and-social-media-use-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/02/18/sentiment-analysis-and-social-media-use-policy/</guid>
      <description>The data scientist should read all agreements and policies of the specific social media site before engaging in data mining for sentiment analysis. The agreements and policies are carefully written by social media companies to protect users, the social company, and the developers. On Twitter&amp;rsquo;s Developers Agreement under &amp;ldquo;VII. Other Important Terms&amp;rdquo; there is a guide on what information is available and how it should not be used (Twitter Developer, May 25, 2018).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government Data Planning - U.S. Compared to Australia</title>
      <link>/post/2019/02/16/government-data-planning-u-s-compared-to-australia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/02/16/government-data-planning-u-s-compared-to-australia/</guid>
      <description>New South Wales (NSW), Australia is one of six states, and each state has a government structure similar to the Commonwealth or Federal branch (Australian government, n.d.). NSW has web resources available that include information on all government services. The site is a one-stop place to find government services related to policy, digital services, and user tools (NSW Government, 2019a). A section of the NSW website, under the &amp;ldquo;policy,&amp;rdquo; is the Data and Information services discussed in this paper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>State, Local, Federal Data Social Media Sources</title>
      <link>/post/2019/02/11/state-local-federal-data-sources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/02/11/state-local-federal-data-sources/</guid>
      <description>The City and County of Denver have a social media policy, and the council does encourage social media usage; however, it must be in line with the local government&amp;rsquo;s mission (City and County of Denver, n.d.). The policy states the social media is not an official government communication and does not guarantee information accuracy and completeness (City and County of Denver, n.d). The social media provided on external sites is a public service; thus, mining data is acceptable.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>