<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R techniques on Bryan Schafroth Portfolio</title>
    <link>/tags/r-techniques/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R techniques on Bryan Schafroth Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/r-techniques/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Different Graphs for Plotting Data in R</title>
      <link>/post/2018/08/19/different-graphs-for-plotting-data-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/08/19/different-graphs-for-plotting-data-in-r/</guid>
      <description>R Graph Plotting SystemThis brief analysis demonstrates the quick ways to look at data by plotting the data points using R and ggplot2. There are four small datasets used in displaying the individual data characteristics. The point is fast and simplistic plot to reveal the represented data.
Load the Librarieslibrary(datasets)library(tidyverse)Air Quality Plotwith(airquality, {plot(Temp, Ozone, pch=19, col=&amp;quot;grey&amp;quot;, main = &amp;quot;Base R - Ozone and Temperature&amp;quot;)lines(loess.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical Clustering (HCA)</title>
      <link>/post/2018/08/04/hierarchical-clustering-hca/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/08/04/hierarchical-clustering-hca/</guid>
      <description>Hierarchical ClusteringThe hierarchical agglomerative clustering starts with each observation as a cluster and pairs two at a time until all clusters are merged into one single cluster. The number of clusters is not known or specified in advance. The distance between all pairs of points in the data is recorded. There is a dendrogram (upside down tree structure) that is the output of the grouping of clusters. It represents and shows how many clusters were found in the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Analysis - Plotting Graphics</title>
      <link>/post/2018/07/29/r-analysis-plotting-graphics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/07/29/r-analysis-plotting-graphics/</guid>
      <description>R Graphics for Exploring DataThe graphics device prints the graphics to screen or into a file type read by other apps. The screen device is on our computers. For windows its windows(), mac its quartz() and Linux its x11(). I am assuming this is built into the R functions plot(), xyplot(), and qplot() when we use them to plot. The other “devices” are the file types that are created by the device.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the dplyr Package in R for Simple Data Analysis</title>
      <link>/post/2018/07/04/using-the-dplyr-package-in-r-for-simple-data-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/07/04/using-the-dplyr-package-in-r-for-simple-data-analysis/</guid>
      <description>This article will briefly describe the dplyr package in R and the simple functions to analyze data with R for data analytics. The dplyr package in R is used for data manipulation and transformation because, typically, the data is not in a usable form. The package is useful for exploratory data analysis and a method of statistical analysis using graphical techniques. Some of the benefits are:
get insights from the data intuitivelyfind hidden trendsfind outliers and anomalous datatest assumptionshelp develop models that the data will fitThe dplyr package is used by many data scientists and analysts to manipulate data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>