<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R techniques on Bryan Schafroth Portfolio</title>
    <link>/tags/r-techniques/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R techniques on Bryan Schafroth Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/r-techniques/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical Clustering (HCA)</title>
      <link>/post/2018/08/04/hierarchical-clustering-hca/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/08/04/hierarchical-clustering-hca/</guid>
      <description>Hierarchical ClusteringThe hierarchical agglomerative clustering starts with each observation as a cluster and pairs two at a time until all clusters are merged into one single cluster. The number of clusters is not known or specified in advance. The distance between all pairs of points in the data is recorded. There is a dendrogram (upside down tree structure) that is the output of the grouping of clusters. It represents and shows how many clusters were found in the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Analysis - Plotting Graphics</title>
      <link>/post/2018/07/29/r-analysis-plotting-graphics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/07/29/r-analysis-plotting-graphics/</guid>
      <description>R Graphics for Exploring DataThe R package used is the “datasets” package that contains all of the data sets used for these examples. The analysis demonstrate the base plotting abilities of RStudio.
This section uses the iris data set. The first plot is a summary of the base plotting capabilities.
library(datasets)str(iris)## &amp;#39;data.frame&amp;#39;: 150 obs. of 5 variables:## $ Sepal.Length: num 5.1 4.9 4.7 4.6 5 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the dplyr Package in R for Simple Data Analysis</title>
      <link>/post/2018/07/04/using-the-dplyr-package-in-r-for-simple-data-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/07/04/using-the-dplyr-package-in-r-for-simple-data-analysis/</guid>
      <description>This article will briefly describe the dplyr package in R and the simple functions to analyze data with R for data analytics. The dplyr package in R is used for data manipulation and transformation because, typically, the data is not in a usable form. The package is useful for exploratory data analysis and a method of statistical analysis using graphical techniques. Some of the benefits are:
get insights from the data intuitivelyfind hidden trendsfind outliers and anomalous datatest assumptionshelp develop models that the data will fitThe dplyr package is used by many data scientists and analysts to manipulate data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>