<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Random Forest on Bryan Schafroth Portfolio</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4321/tags/random-forest/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Random Forest on Bryan Schafroth Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4321/tags/random-forest/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Classification Problem using Machine Learning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2018/10/21/classification-problem-using-machine-learning-forest-cover-type/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2018/10/21/classification-problem-using-machine-learning-forest-cover-type/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div id=&#34;introduction&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Introduction&lt;/h4&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article will present a machine learning problem and the concept behind solving the problem. The project will go into detail about the early exploratory steps and build a machine learning model that can be used in production to categorize data. This project is to categorize seven Rocky Mountain tree types found in the forests. In this project, we will use old legacy data from the 1990s and use modern machine learning methods to categorize the data. The owner of the data can migrate the newly categorized data over to their modern cloud database. In the late 1990s, data was collected for mapping by survey methods and done manually in the field. Though in the modern era, we can use high-resolution aerial imagery, GPS, and techniques in GIS systems to categorize cartographic data using the tools of computer vision and machine learning. However, for practical purposes, there are clients and owners of legacy data on old systems. Owners would like to migrate data from legacy systems into modern databases such as the cloud. The utilization of the data through modern computing is of use to the owners. One of the issues is how to categorize the vast amount of legacy data. Automating the categorization process with machine learning is the method proposed in this article.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Random Forest and Decision Tree Analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2018/06/01/random-forest-and-decision-tree-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2018/06/01/random-forest-and-decision-tree-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div id=&#34;decision-tree-and-random-forest&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Decision Tree and Random Forest&lt;/h3&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This analysis will utilize the data set from &lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.ics.uci.edu/ml/machine-learning-databases/wine-quality/winequality-red.csv&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://archive.ics.uci.edu/ml/machine-learning-databases/wine-quality/winequality-red.csv&lt;/a&gt; and the purpose is to find the differences between the decision tree method and the random forest method for predicting wine quality from the 11 variables that indicate each wine’s chemical readings. The 12th variable is the quality rating given to these 1599 wines and is used as the predictor in the models. The quality has ratings from 3 to 8. To make the ratings work in the models there will be three groups “Fair” = (3-4), “Satisfactory” = (5-6), and “Excellent” = (7-8).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
