<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Bryan Schafroth Portfolio</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Bryan Schafroth Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Informed Consent and Data Science</title>
      <link>/post/2019/01/23/informed-consent-and-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/01/23/informed-consent-and-data-science/</guid>
      <description>This retrospective study is from the Netherlands. See the published research article in the reference section below. The article review uses data from 2000 to 2016 and identifies 2,037 children that were previous patients at a university hospital (Draijer, Bosch, Wiegman, Sjouke, Benninga, &amp;amp; Koot, 2018, p.174). The kids screened for liver disease with the goal of this study to use a higher-performing algorithm that improves the accuracy in detecting the condition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science and a Code of Ethics</title>
      <link>/post/2019/01/20/data-science-and-a-code-of-ethics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/01/20/data-science-and-a-code-of-ethics/</guid>
      <description>The Association for Computing Machinery (ACM) created the ACM Code of Ethics and Professional Conduct to direct computing professionals to act and promote ethical behavior in the profession (ACM, 2018). The ACM Code of Ethics and Professional Conduct is in four sections: General Ethical Principles, Professional Responsibilities, Professional Leadership Principles, and Compliance With the Code (ACM, 2018). This paper will discuss the seven General Ethical Principles and classify them into the three major areas of ethics, privacy, and social justice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ethical Issues a Data Scientist Could Face</title>
      <link>/post/2019/01/15/ethical-issues-a-data-scientist-could-face/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/01/15/ethical-issues-a-data-scientist-could-face/</guid>
      <description>The Association for Computing Machinery (ACM) has a code of ethics and professional conduct guidelines (ACM, 2018). The &amp;ldquo;code&amp;rdquo; is for people that work in computing and a guide to consider when decision making. Section 2.9 outlines the need to design systems that are very secure and recognizing that breaches of computer systems can be malevolent to many people and organizations (ACM, 2018). The ACM states not to roll out systems without thorough testing of security exploits (2018).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experimental Design</title>
      <link>/post/2017/10/01/experimental-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017/10/01/experimental-design/</guid>
      <description>In the book Encyclopedia of Behavioral Medicine, Turner describes experimental design from a clinical perspective “as an experiment with a series of observations made under conditions in which the research scientist controls the influences of interest”, Turner, 2013. The randomized trial is a classic example of experimental design. The data is randomized to one of two or more experimental groups. Then the significant differences between the sets are analyzed. (Turner, 2013) The Completely Randomized Design, Randomized Block Design, and Factorial design are three experimental designs, and analysis of variance (ANOVA) will tell us whether or not there is a difference between the means of one or more independent categorical groups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a junior level data scientist professional with a Master’s Degree in Data Science. I have demonstrated abilities to extract insights from data and use them to make recommendations based on statistical modeling. I enjoy defining and solving problems by distilling abstract/complex theories and datasets into simple terms and draft meaningful easy-to-understand outcomes for both technical and non-technical audiences.
In addition to my Data Science profession, I have a background in civil engineering.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>