<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Exploration on Bryan Schafroth Portfolio</title>
    <link>/tags/data-exploration/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Exploration on Bryan Schafroth Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/data-exploration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Case Study - Mobile Photo Analysis</title>
      <link>/post/2018/08/26/case-study-mobile-photo-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/08/26/case-study-mobile-photo-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Case StudyCan a mobile phone application identify a species of a plant by photo analysis?
This analysis is hypothetical and analyzes the feasibility of developing a mobile application for mobile phones (that photograph and store pictures) and identify flower pictures stored in memory. This exercise is a small part of a project and will only focus on the exploratory elements of a sample dataset called iris.
For a successful application, the algorithm shall correctly identify a flower species from a photo on the user’s phone using an image recognition model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Different Graphs for Plotting Data in R</title>
      <link>/post/2018/08/19/different-graphs-for-plotting-data-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/08/19/different-graphs-for-plotting-data-in-r/</guid>
      <description>R Graph Plotting SystemThis brief analysis demonstrates the quick ways to look at data by plotting the data points using R and ggplot2. There are four small datasets used in displaying the individual data characteristics. The point is fast and simplistic plot to reveal the represented data.
Load the Librarieslibrary(datasets)library(tidyverse)Air Quality Plotwith(airquality, {plot(Temp, Ozone, pch=19, col=&amp;quot;grey&amp;quot;, main = &amp;quot;Base R - Ozone and Temperature&amp;quot;)lines(loess.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>K-Means Clustering Analysis</title>
      <link>/post/2018/08/12/k-means-clustering-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/08/12/k-means-clustering-analysis/</guid>
      <description>K-Means ClusteringThe first section uses the iris data set and k-means clustering starting with 3 cluster centers and an nstart of 15. The results are displayed below in the fit object. There are 3 clusters sized 50, 62, and 38. The within sum of squares by cluster is 88.4% and the smaller number (15.15, 39.82, &amp;amp; 23.87) indicates how closely related objects are in the clusters. The first cluster has the most related objects and the second cluster has the lesser of related objects mostly taken from the third cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical Clustering (HCA)</title>
      <link>/post/2018/08/04/hierarchical-clustering-hca/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/08/04/hierarchical-clustering-hca/</guid>
      <description>Hierarchical ClusteringThe hierarchical agglomerative clustering starts with each observation as a cluster and pairs two at a time until all clusters are merged into one single cluster. The number of clusters is not known or specified in advance. The distance between all pairs of points in the data is recorded. There is a dendrogram (upside down tree structure) that is the output of the grouping of clusters. It represents and shows how many clusters were found in the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Analysis - Plotting Graphics</title>
      <link>/post/2018/07/29/r-analysis-plotting-graphics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/07/29/r-analysis-plotting-graphics/</guid>
      <description>R Graphics for Exploring DataThe graphics device prints the graphics to screen or into a file type read by other apps. The screen device is on our computers. For windows its windows(), mac its quartz() and Linux its x11(). I am assuming this is built into the R functions plot(), xyplot(), and qplot() when we use them to plot. The other “devices” are the file types that are created by the device.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Analysis - Exploratory Graphics</title>
      <link>/post/2018/07/22/data-analysis-exploratory-graphics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/07/22/data-analysis-exploratory-graphics/</guid>
      <description>Exploratory Graphics in RThe focus of this analysis is on the ways to graph data set variables. The first section uses the EPA data set retrieved from: https://github.com/jtleek/modules/blob/master/04_ExploratoryAnalysis/exploratoryGraphs/data/avgpm25.csv the data was imported into a csv file and then used for this first section. Code notes for explaination.
The first part uses the RStudio base functionality to plot graphics then we use maps, lattice, and ggplot2 to compare and contrast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploratory Data Analysis - EPA Ozone Data</title>
      <link>/post/2018/07/14/exploratory-data-analysis-epa-ozone-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/07/14/exploratory-data-analysis-epa-ozone-data/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThis exploratory data analysis will use the “hourly_44201_2014” data set obtained from the web site: https://aqs.epa.gov/aqsweb/airdata/download_files.html#Raw The data is “Criteria Gases” and labeled “Ozone (44201)” for this particular data set. The data is loaded into RStudio and shows 9,060,694 rows and 24 variables.
There are 24 variables in this data set. Looking through the variables, we can see the first four are coded presumably by the EPA. The Latitude, Longitude, and Datum are geo-location data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Preprocessing - Diamonds Dataset</title>
      <link>/post/2018/05/13/data-preprocessing-diamonds-dataset/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/05/13/data-preprocessing-diamonds-dataset/</guid>
      <description>Data PreprocessingThe following analysis is of the diamonds dataset downloaded from the tidyverse/ggplot2 Github repository. The data is in a .csv file. The purpose of the analysis is to explore the data and perform data exploration, cleaning, and preprocessing needed for modeling. Data cleaning and preprocessing involves checking for missing records, removing missing data, imputing missing data, converting categorical variables with one-hot encoding or dummy variables, scaling data, normalizing data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>