<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>data preprocessing on Bryan Schafroth Portfolio</title>
    <link>/tags/data-preprocessing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in data preprocessing on Bryan Schafroth Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/data-preprocessing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Different Graphs for Plotting Data in R</title>
      <link>/post/2018/08/19/different-graphs-for-plotting-data-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/08/19/different-graphs-for-plotting-data-in-r/</guid>
      <description>R Graph Plotting SystemThis brief analysis demonstrates the quick ways to look at data by plotting the data points using R and ggplot2. There are four small datasets used in displaying the individual data characteristics. The point is fast and simplistic plot to reveal the represented data.
Load the Librarieslibrary(datasets)library(tidyverse)Air Quality Plotwith(airquality, {plot(Temp, Ozone, pch=19, col=&amp;quot;grey&amp;quot;, main = &amp;quot;Base R - Ozone and Temperature&amp;quot;)lines(loess.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Analysis - Plotting Graphics</title>
      <link>/post/2018/07/29/r-analysis-plotting-graphics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/07/29/r-analysis-plotting-graphics/</guid>
      <description>R Graphics for Exploring DataThe graphics device prints the graphics to screen or into a file type read by other apps. The screen device is on our computers. For windows its windows(), mac its quartz() and Linux its x11(). I am assuming this is built into the R functions plot(), xyplot(), and qplot() when we use them to plot. The other “devices” are the file types that are created by the device.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Analysis - Exploratory Graphics</title>
      <link>/post/2018/07/22/data-analysis-exploratory-graphics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/07/22/data-analysis-exploratory-graphics/</guid>
      <description>Exploratory Graphics in RThe focus of this analysis is on the ways to graph data set variables. The first section uses the EPA data set retrieved from: https://github.com/jtleek/modules/blob/master/04_ExploratoryAnalysis/exploratoryGraphs/data/avgpm25.csv the data was imported into a csv file and then used for this first section. Code notes for explaination.
The first part uses the RStudio base functionality to plot graphics then we use maps, lattice, and ggplot2 to compare and contrast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Preprocessing - Diamonds Dataset</title>
      <link>/post/2018/05/13/data-preprocessing-diamonds-dataset/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/05/13/data-preprocessing-diamonds-dataset/</guid>
      <description>Data PreprocessingThe following analysis is of the diamonds dataset downloaded from the tidyverse/ggplot2 Github repository. The data is in a .csv file. The purpose of the analysis is to explore the data and perform data exploration, cleaning, and preprocessing needed for modeling. Data cleaning and preprocessing involves checking for missing records, removing missing data, imputing missing data, converting categorical variables with one-hot encoding or dummy variables, scaling data, normalizing data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>