<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Government Social Media Data on Bryan Schafroth Portfolio</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4321/tags/government-social-media-data/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Government Social Media Data on Bryan Schafroth Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4321/tags/government-social-media-data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>State, Local, Federal Data Social Media Sources</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2019/02/11/state-local-federal-data-sources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2019/02/11/state-local-federal-data-sources/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;    The City and County of Denver have a social media policy, and the council does encourage social media usage; however, it must be in line with the local government&amp;rsquo;s mission (City and County of Denver, n.d.). The policy states the social media is not an official government communication and does not guarantee information accuracy and completeness (City and County of Denver, n.d). The social media provided on external sites is a public service; thus, mining data is acceptable. There is no guarantee that social media posts are 100% accurate and complete; therefore, when using the data in research, be transparent about this source of data and its accuracy (or lack of). The City of Denver&amp;rsquo;s social media sites are subject to public record laws; thus, any information attached to the account is &amp;ldquo;subject to public disclosure under Citywide Colorado Open Records Fee Policy (CORA)&amp;rdquo; (City and County of Denver, n.d).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
