<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Analysis on Bryan Schafroth Portfolio</title>
    <link>/categories/data-analysis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Analysis on Bryan Schafroth Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/data-analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>R Analysis - Plotting Graphics</title>
      <link>/post/2018/07/29/r-analysis-plotting-graphics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/07/29/r-analysis-plotting-graphics/</guid>
      <description>R Graphics for Exploring DataThe R package used is the “datasets” package that contains all of the data sets used for these examples. The analysis demonstrate the base plotting abilities of RStudio.
This section uses the iris data set. The first plot is a summary of the base plotting capabilities.
library(datasets)str(iris)## &amp;#39;data.frame&amp;#39;: 150 obs. of 5 variables:## $ Sepal.Length: num 5.1 4.9 4.7 4.6 5 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Analysis - Exploratory Graphics</title>
      <link>/post/2018/07/22/data-analysis-exploratory-graphics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/07/22/data-analysis-exploratory-graphics/</guid>
      <description>Exploratory Graphics in RThe focus of this analysis is on the ways to graph data set variables. The first section uses the EPA data set retrieved from: https://github.com/jtleek/modules/blob/master/04_ExploratoryAnalysis/exploratoryGraphs/data/avgpm25.csv the data was imported into a csv file and then used for this first section. Code notes for explaination.
The first part uses the RStudio base functionality to plot graphics then we use maps, lattice, and ggplot2 to compare and contrast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Exploration - The Chicago Dataset</title>
      <link>/post/2018/07/07/data-exploration-the-chicago-dataset/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/07/07/data-exploration-the-chicago-dataset/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThis article is about using the tidyverse package in R to explore data. The Chicago dataset is the basis for this analysis. The data is air quality measurements taken over 19 years. The focus is on using the dplyr package to do the analysis. The dplyr package is part of the tidyverse in R and a suite of tools to analyze, transform, plot, and manipulate data. The base version of R does all of this; however, dplyr will work faster and cost fewer computing resources when used on big data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the dplyr Package in R for Simple Data Analysis</title>
      <link>/post/2018/07/04/using-the-dplyr-package-in-r-for-simple-data-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/07/04/using-the-dplyr-package-in-r-for-simple-data-analysis/</guid>
      <description>This article will briefly describe the dplyr package in R and the simple functions to analyze data with R for data analytics. The dplyr package in R is used for data manipulation and transformation because, typically, the data is not in a usable form. The package is useful for exploratory data analysis and a method of statistical analysis using graphical techniques. Some of the benefits are:
get insights from the data intuitivelyfind hidden trendsfind outliers and anomalous datatest assumptionshelp develop models that the data will fitThe dplyr package is used by many data scientists and analysts to manipulate data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple data exploration with base R functions</title>
      <link>/post/2018/07/02/simple-data-exploration-with-base-r-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/07/02/simple-data-exploration-with-base-r-functions/</guid>
      <description>Exploring the data with base R functionsThe purpose of this post is to show the basic fucntions in R to start a data analysis project. I look at the iris dataset that comes with Rstudio shown below.This briefly covers head(), str(), attributes(), summary(), dim(), names(), indexing [], table(), and plot() functions that come with base R. Simple to use.
Load the iris datasetdata(&amp;quot;iris&amp;quot;) head()Look at the iris dataset with the head() function and lists the first five rows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Naive Bayes SMS Message Classifier</title>
      <link>/post/2018/05/27/naive-bayes-sms-message-classifier/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/05/27/naive-bayes-sms-message-classifier/</guid>
      <description>Naive Bayes SMS Message ClassifierThis analysis demonstrates the naive bayes classifier in determining the spam or ham status of 4837 SMS messages. The data set is retrieved from: http://archive.ics.uci.edu/ml/datasets/SMS+Spam+Collection. The data needs explicit cleaning to prepare it to run through a naive bayes classifier. A training and test set is created to train and validate the predictive ability ofy the model. There are summary plots of the words found in abundance in the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>K-Nearest Neighbor (KNN) - Heart Disease Dataset</title>
      <link>/post/2018/05/20/k-nearest-neighbor-knn-heart-disease-dataset/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/05/20/k-nearest-neighbor-knn-heart-disease-dataset/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to K-Nearest NeighborKNN is a supervised learning algorithm and uses a training sample from the dataset, which classifies groups into different classes. It is a classifier used to predict the level of an unknown point (observation) and does this by measuring the points nearest to the unknown point. It works well in measuring the differences between multiple classes that are complex and hard to detect. KNN is considered a simple classification and regression algorithm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Preprocessing - Diamonds Dataset</title>
      <link>/post/2018/05/13/data-preprocessing-diamonds-dataset/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/05/13/data-preprocessing-diamonds-dataset/</guid>
      <description>Data PreprocessingThe following analysis is of the diamonds dataset downloaded from the tidyverse/ggplot2 Github repository. The data is in a .csv file. The purpose of the analysis is to explore the data and perform data exploration, cleaning, and preprocessing needed for modeling. Data cleaning and preprocessing involves checking for missing records, removing missing data, imputing missing data, converting categorical variables with one-hot encoding or dummy variables, scaling data, normalizing data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>