<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Analysis on Bryan Schafroth Portfolio</title>
    <link>/categories/data-analysis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Analysis on Bryan Schafroth Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/data-analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Exploration - The Chicago Dataset</title>
      <link>/post/2018/07/07/data-exploration-the-chicago-dataset/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/07/07/data-exploration-the-chicago-dataset/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThis article is about using the tidyverse package in R to explore data. The Chicago dataset is the basis for this analysis. The data is air quality measurements taken over 19 years. The focus is on using the dplyr package to do the analysis. The dplyr package is part of the tidyverse in R and a suite of tools to analyze, transform, plot, and manipulate data. The base version of R does all of this; however, dplyr will work faster and cost fewer computing resources when used on big data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the dplyr Package in R for Simple Data Analysis</title>
      <link>/post/2018/07/04/using-the-dplyr-package-in-r-for-simple-data-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/07/04/using-the-dplyr-package-in-r-for-simple-data-analysis/</guid>
      <description>This article will briefly describe the dplyr package in R and the simple functions to analyze data with R for data analytics. The dplyr package in R is used for data manipulation and transformation because, typically, the data is not in a usable form. The package is useful for exploratory data analysis and a method of statistical analysis using graphical techniques. Some of the benefits are:
get insights from the data intuitivelyfind hidden trendsfind outliers and anomalous datatest assumptionshelp develop models that the data will fitThe dplyr package is used by many data scientists and analysts to manipulate data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple data exploration with base R functions</title>
      <link>/post/2018/07/02/simple-data-exploration-with-base-r-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/07/02/simple-data-exploration-with-base-r-functions/</guid>
      <description>Exploring the data with base R functionsThe purpose of this post is to show the basic fucntions in R to start a data analysis project. I look at the iris dataset that comes with Rstudio shown below.This briefly covers head(), str(), attributes(), summary(), dim(), names(), indexing [], table(), and plot() functions that come with base R. Simple to use.
Load the iris datasetdata(&amp;quot;iris&amp;quot;) head()Look at the iris dataset with the head() function and lists the first five rows.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>