<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>government data resources on Bryan Schafroth Portfolio</title>
    <link>/tags/government-data-resources/</link>
    <description>Recent content in government data resources on Bryan Schafroth Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/government-data-resources/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Data.gov and Applications that Solve Problems</title>
      <link>/post/2019/03/04/using-data-gov-and-applications-that-solve-problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/03/04/using-data-gov-and-applications-that-solve-problems/</guid>
      <description>On the data.gov application site, there are a handful of examples where the open data from data.gov can provide a service to consumers. There is a good sampling of applications voluntarily submitted to the site for the chance to be featured. Data.gov does not say they endorse the applications.
 One of the many applications is Redfin. I recently learned about Redfin on television, and it was a commercial for the company.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government Data Planning - U.S. Compared to Australia</title>
      <link>/post/2019/02/16/government-data-planning-u-s-compared-to-australia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/02/16/government-data-planning-u-s-compared-to-australia/</guid>
      <description>New South Wales (NSW), Australia is one of six states, and each state has a government structure similar to the Commonwealth or Federal branch (Australian government, n.d.). NSW has web resources available that include information on all government services. The site is a one-stop place to find government services related to policy, digital services, and user tools (NSW Government, 2019a). A section of the NSW website, under the &amp;ldquo;policy,&amp;rdquo; is the Data and Information services discussed in this paper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government Regulations Slide Presentation</title>
      <link>/post/2019/02/07/government-regulations-slide-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/02/07/government-regulations-slide-presentation/</guid>
      <description>This article is a slide presentation discussing government regulations covering the legal aspects of privacy. It covers the industry regulated why it was created and other interesting information. A direct link to the slide presentation can be found here: Government Regulations Slide Presentation
Or hover mouse over slide and scroll through:
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>