<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Government Data Resources on Bryan Schafroth Portfolio</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4321/tags/government-data-resources/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Government Data Resources on Bryan Schafroth Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4321/tags/government-data-resources/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using Data.gov and Applications that Solve Problems</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2019/03/04/using-data-gov-and-applications-that-solve-problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2019/03/04/using-data-gov-and-applications-that-solve-problems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;    On the data.gov application site, there are a handful of examples where the open data from data.gov can provide a service to consumers. There is a good sampling of applications voluntarily submitted to the site for the chance to be featured. Data.gov does not say they endorse the applications.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;    One of the many applications is Redfin. I recently learned about Redfin on television, and it was a commercial for the company. On the data.gov site, there is a good description of the application. Redfin uses the data from The Department of Housing and Urban Development, The Department of the Interior, and the U.S. Geological Survey(USGS) (Data.gov, 2019). The Department of the Interior includes the USGS and not sure why it is listed separately on data.gov. One of the links is dead for the Map of the U.S. (most likely the USGS), and the Homebuyer Activities Report link gives an old dataset from March of 2015 (Data.gov, 2015). Not sure what to think about this, data.gov doesn’t update the site? Looking into the Investor Relations on Redfin, they launched in 2006 (Redfin Investor Relations, 2019), and I guess they used open data in 2015?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Government Data Planning - U.S. Compared to Australia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2019/02/16/government-data-planning-u-s-compared-to-australia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2019/02/16/government-data-planning-u-s-compared-to-australia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;    New South Wales (NSW), Australia is one of six states, and each state has a government structure similar to the Commonwealth or Federal branch (Australian government, n.d.). NSW has web resources available that include information on all government services. The site is a one-stop place to find government services related to policy, digital services, and user tools (NSW Government, 2019a). A section of the NSW website, under the &amp;ldquo;policy,&amp;rdquo; is the Data and Information services discussed in this paper. This article describes the NSW Data and Information plan and describes similar data and information systems in Colorado and the U.S. Government as a comparison.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Body-Worn Camera&#39;s &amp; Privacy in Law Enforcement</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2019/02/13/body-worn-camera-s-privacy-in-law-enforcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2019/02/13/body-worn-camera-s-privacy-in-law-enforcement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This presentation explores the Bureau of Justice Statistics and discusses privacy issues that are related to data obtained from Law Enforcement Agencies use of body-worn camera’s. Direct Link to slides:&#xD;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bryanschafroth.com/slides/govregdata.html#1&#34;&gt;Body-Worn Cameras Slide Presentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Or hover mouse over slide and scroll through:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.bryanschafroth.com/slides/bodycamlaw.html#1&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; height=&#34;400px&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Government Regulations Slide Presentation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2019/02/07/government-regulations-slide-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2019/02/07/government-regulations-slide-presentation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This article is a slide presentation discussing government regulations covering the legal aspects of privacy. It covers the industry regulated why it was created and other interesting information. A direct link to the slide presentation can be found here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bryanschafroth.com/slides/govregdata.html#1&#34;&gt;Government Regulations Slide Presentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Or hover mouse over slide and scroll through:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.bryanschafroth.com/slides/govregdata.html#1&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; height=&#34;400px&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
