<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>data collection on Bryan Schafroth Portfolio</title>
    <link>/tags/data-collection/</link>
    <description>Recent content in data collection on Bryan Schafroth Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/data-collection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Data – Annual Crime Dataset 2015</title>
      <link>/post/2019/03/09/open-data-annual-crime-dataset-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/03/09/open-data-annual-crime-dataset-2015/</guid>
      <description>Data.gov has a “Local Government” (data.gov, 2019b) section among fourteen available topics to obtain data. In the “All Local Government section, as of this writing, there are 17,209 datasets (data.gov, 2019a). Filtering found in the “Organizations” or “Publishers” tab will isolate all the data available for Austin, Texas. Not all U.S. States, cities, and counties are in this resource, which does not indicate the data are not available. A direct way to find local data is to go to the city, state, or county websites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Body-Worn Camera&#39;s &amp; Privacy in Law Enforcement</title>
      <link>/post/2019/02/13/body-worn-camera-s-privacy-in-law-enforcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/02/13/body-worn-camera-s-privacy-in-law-enforcement/</guid>
      <description>This presentation explores the Bureau of Justice Statistics and discusses privacy issues that are related to data obtained from Law Enforcement Agencies use of body-worn camera’s. Direct Link to slides:Body-Worn Cameras Slide Presentation
Or hover mouse over slide and scroll through:
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Case Study on Data Collection: Harvesting Personalities Online</title>
      <link>/post/2019/01/27/case-study-on-data-collection-harvesting-personalities-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/01/27/case-study-on-data-collection-harvesting-personalities-online/</guid>
      <description>Raicu wrote a case study for the Santa Clara University discussing the data analytics firm Cambridge Analytica who provided marketing services for various political campaigns (2016). The case study reveals Cambridge Analytica assumed the personality type of nearly all of the registered voters in the U.S. (Raicu, 2016). The study attempts to answer how Cambridge Analytica determined the personality type of 190 million people who were registered to vote across the U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple data exploration with base R functions</title>
      <link>/post/2018/07/02/simple-data-exploration-with-base-r-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/07/02/simple-data-exploration-with-base-r-functions/</guid>
      <description>Exploring the data with base R functionsThe purpose of this post is to show the basic fucntions in R to start a data analysis project. I look at the iris dataset that comes with Rstudio shown below.This briefly covers head(), str(), attributes(), summary(), dim(), names(), indexing [], table(), and plot() functions that come with base R. Simple to use.
Load the iris datasetdata(&amp;quot;iris&amp;quot;) head()Look at the iris dataset with the head() function and lists the first five rows.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>