<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ethics on Bryan Schafroth Portfolio</title>
    <link>/categories/ethics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ethics on Bryan Schafroth Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/ethics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Case Study on Genome Privacy</title>
      <link>/post/2020/04/08/a-case-study-on-genome-privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/04/08/a-case-study-on-genome-privacy/</guid>
      <description>The premise of this article is Walser-Kuntz, Deel, and Singer&amp;rsquo;s case study in genome privacy (2005). The authors of the case study state that biosciences have been able to isolate the single nucleotide polymorphism (SNP) as part of humans&amp;rsquo; DNA markers (Walser-Kuntz, Deel, &amp;amp; Singer, 2005). The SNPs have three uses, according to Walser-Kuntz, Deel, &amp;amp; Singer: genetic markers for disease, specialized applications in medicine, and mapping human evolution (p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Informed Consent and Data Science</title>
      <link>/post/2019/01/23/informed-consent-and-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/01/23/informed-consent-and-data-science/</guid>
      <description>This retrospective study is from the Netherlands. See the published research article in the reference section below. The article review uses data from 2000 to 2016 and identifies 2,037 children that were previous patients at a university hospital (Draijer, Bosch, Wiegman, Sjouke, Benninga, &amp;amp; Koot, 2018, p.174). The kids screened for liver disease with the goal of this study to use a higher-performing algorithm that improves the accuracy in detecting the condition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science and a Code of Ethics</title>
      <link>/post/2019/01/20/data-science-and-a-code-of-ethics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/01/20/data-science-and-a-code-of-ethics/</guid>
      <description>The Association for Computing Machinery (ACM) created the ACM Code of Ethics and Professional Conduct to direct computing professionals to act and promote ethical behavior in the profession (ACM, 2018). The ACM Code of Ethics and Professional Conduct is in four sections: General Ethical Principles, Professional Responsibilities, Professional Leadership Principles, and Compliance With the Code (ACM, 2018). This paper will discuss the seven General Ethical Principles and classify them into the three major areas of ethics, privacy, and social justice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ethical Issues a Data Scientist Could Face</title>
      <link>/post/2019/01/15/ethical-issues-a-data-scientist-could-face/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/01/15/ethical-issues-a-data-scientist-could-face/</guid>
      <description>The Association for Computing Machinery (ACM) has a code of ethics and professional conduct guidelines (ACM, 2018). The &amp;ldquo;code&amp;rdquo; is for people that work in computing and a guide to consider when decision making. Section 2.9 outlines the need to design systems that are very secure and recognizing that breaches of computer systems can be malevolent to many people and organizations (ACM, 2018). The ACM states not to roll out systems without thorough testing of security exploits (2018).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>