<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ethics on Bryan Schafroth Portfolio</title>
    <link>/categories/ethics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ethics on Bryan Schafroth Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/ethics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Employee Ethical Breach</title>
      <link>/post/2019/01/28/employee-ethical-breach/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/01/28/employee-ethical-breach/</guid>
      <description>The article is from August of 2018 and found in the Healthcare IT News, among others. The ethics breach was by a Canadian pharmacist in Nova Scotia. The pharmacist caught accessing the health records of approximately 46 patients that the pharmacist knew (Minion, 2018). The ethics breach was spread over two years until the Canadian Privacy Commission discovered what was happening though standard audits. The article said this pharmacist had looked at the records of former classmates, her doctor, and a person whom she had a car accident with, her kid&amp;rsquo;s therapist, her coworkers, family members, and her kid&amp;rsquo;s girlfriend (Minion, 2018).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Case Study on Genome Privacy</title>
      <link>/post/2019/01/27/a-case-study-on-genome-privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/01/27/a-case-study-on-genome-privacy/</guid>
      <description>The premise of this article is Walser-Kuntz, Deel, and Singer&amp;rsquo;s case study in genome privacy (2005). The authors of the case study state that biosciences have been able to isolate the single nucleotide polymorphism (SNP) as part of humans&amp;rsquo; DNA markers (Walser-Kuntz, Deel, &amp;amp; Singer, 2005). The SNPs have three uses, according to Walser-Kuntz, Deel, &amp;amp; Singer: genetic markers for disease, specialized applications in medicine, and mapping human evolution (p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Case Study on Data Collection: Harvesting Personalities Online</title>
      <link>/post/2019/01/27/case-study-on-data-collection-harvesting-personalities-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/01/27/case-study-on-data-collection-harvesting-personalities-online/</guid>
      <description>Raicu wrote a case study for the Santa Clara University discussing the data analytics firm Cambridge Analytica who provided marketing services for various political campaigns (2016). The case study reveals Cambridge Analytica assumed the personality type of nearly all of the registered voters in the U.S. (Raicu, 2016). The study attempts to answer how Cambridge Analytica determined the personality type of 190 million people who were registered to vote across the U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Informed Consent and Data Science</title>
      <link>/post/2019/01/23/informed-consent-and-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/01/23/informed-consent-and-data-science/</guid>
      <description>This retrospective study is from the Netherlands. See the published research article in the reference section below. The article review uses data from 2000 to 2016 and identifies 2,037 children that were previous patients at a university hospital (Draijer, Bosch, Wiegman, Sjouke, Benninga, &amp;amp; Koot, 2018, p.174). The kids screened for liver disease with the goal of this study to use a higher-performing algorithm that improves the accuracy in detecting the condition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science and a Code of Ethics</title>
      <link>/post/2019/01/20/data-science-and-a-code-of-ethics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/01/20/data-science-and-a-code-of-ethics/</guid>
      <description>The Association for Computing Machinery (ACM) created the ACM Code of Ethics and Professional Conduct to direct computing professionals to act and promote ethical behavior in the profession (ACM, 2018). The ACM Code of Ethics and Professional Conduct is in four sections: General Ethical Principles, Professional Responsibilities, Professional Leadership Principles, and Compliance With the Code (ACM, 2018). This paper will discuss the seven General Ethical Principles and classify them into the three major areas of ethics, privacy, and social justice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ethical Issues a Data Scientist Could Face</title>
      <link>/post/2019/01/15/ethical-issues-a-data-scientist-could-face/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/01/15/ethical-issues-a-data-scientist-could-face/</guid>
      <description>The Association for Computing Machinery (ACM) has a code of ethics and professional conduct guidelines (ACM, 2018). The &amp;ldquo;code&amp;rdquo; is for people that work in computing and a guide to consider when decision making. Section 2.9 outlines the need to design systems that are very secure and recognizing that breaches of computer systems can be malevolent to many people and organizations (ACM, 2018). The ACM states not to roll out systems without thorough testing of security exploits (2018).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical Clustering (HCA)</title>
      <link>/post/2018/08/04/hierarchical-clustering-hca/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/08/04/hierarchical-clustering-hca/</guid>
      <description>Hierarchical ClusteringThe hierarchical agglomerative clustering starts with each observation as a cluster and pairs two at a time until all clusters are merged into one single cluster. The number of clusters is not known or specified in advance. The distance between all pairs of points in the data is recorded. There is a dendrogram (upside down tree structure) that is the output of the grouping of clusters. It represents and shows how many clusters were found in the data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>